It's you.
是你
The phantom piper!
幽灵风笛手！
No!
不！
No! I'll not go with you!
不！我不跟你走！
Do you hear me, piper? No! Leave me!
你听到了没, 风笛手？不, 走开！
Leave me. I'll not go with you, do you hear me?
走开．我不跟你走, 你听到了没？
Leave me! No, I'll not go with you!
走开！不, 我不跟你走！
I'll fight you every inch of the way.
我每一步都要跟你斗
I'll not go with you.
我不跟你走
Leave me, piper.
走开, 风笛手
No. Leave me. I'll not go.
不, 走开, 我不走
Agh!
啊
- Polly, what's happened?
- Oh, Doctor, it was horrible!
- Polly, 发生什么事了？  - 哦, 博士, 太吓人了
- A giant creature like a Cyberman!
- It's all right. Don't be frightened.
- 一个赛博人一样的大家伙  - 没事了, 别怕
- Whatever it was, it's gone now.
- It's the... Doctor, the Cyberman was carrying a patient.
- 不管是什么, 现在已经走了 - 那是...博士, 那个赛博人扛着一个病人
- Cyberman? What are you talking about?
- I'm sure it was.
- 赛博人？你在说些什么？  - 我确定是
- I'll not go with you.
- It's OK. It's safe now. Take it easy.
- 我不跟你走  - 没事了, 现在安全了, 放松
She's right. There's another one gone.
她是对的, 又有一个不见了
Sam, Jules, you've got to find these men.
They can't just disappear in a place this size.
Sam, Jules, 你们去找这几个人．他们不可能消失了, 就这么点大个地方
Search every square inch, don't come back
until you find them. Now move.
每一寸都要搜到, 找不到他们就不要回来．快去
Now, supposing you tell me your story? What did you see?
现在, 来跟我说说你的故事？你看到了什么？
I went out to get Jamie some water,
我出去给 Jamie 倒点水
and when I came back,
I saw this giant man or creature or something,
当我回来的时候, 我看到一个高大的人或者生物什么的
just going out of the door,
carrying one of the patients... like a doll.
它正走出门去, 扛着一个我们的病人...像个玩偶一样
- I think it was a Cyberman.
- Forget that part. Then what?
- 我觉得那是个赛博人  - 忘了那个吧．然后呢？
Then nothing. The door shut, and then you came in.
然后没什么了．门关上了, 然后你们进来了
- What do you know about all this?
- Nothing. Absolutely nothing.
- 这一切你都知道些什么？  - 没什么, 什么也不知道
We'll see about that in a minute.
我们稍后再来讨论
- This thing you saw. What was it like?
- It was enormous, and silver.
- 你看见的这个东西, 它是什么样子？  - 很高大, 银色外形
- It had holes in its head for eyes, like a robot.
- A robot?
- 脑袋上眼睛那个位置有洞, 像个机器人一样  - 像个机器人?
But the Cybermen were all killed when Mondas blew up.
但 Mondas 爆炸的时候赛博人都死了啊
Stop this Cyberman nonsense!
别胡说赛博人那些东西了
There were Cybermen, every child knows that,
but they were destroyed ages ago!
以前是有赛博人, 每个小孩子都知道．但他们几十年前就被消灭了！
（注:  赛博人初次出现于1986年, 试图夺取地球, 后与母星
Mondas 一起毁灭．参见04x01 第十行星 The Tenth Planet）
- So we all thought.
- That's enough.
- 我们都这么想  - 别再说了
Let's have a little calm thinking.
我们都冷静地想一想
For the past two weeks,
a complete unknown disease has appeared in the base.
过去两个星期以来, 一种完全未知的疾病出现在这个基地
People drop in their tracks
and develop a black pattern on their skin.
人在工作岗位上倒下, 皮肤上长出黑色的条纹
Then some of the patients disappear, right?
然后又有一些病人消失了, 对不？
They can't leave the base without wearing spacesuits,
and there are no spacesuits missing. So where are they?
不穿太空服的花他们不可能离开基地, 但又没有太空服丢失．那他们在哪儿？
- I must say, It does sound a little odd.
- More than a little.
- 我得说, 这事听着是有一点点奇怪  - 不是一点点
I do know one thing - a new disease starts,
people disappear, and then you turn up.
我倒的确知道一件事情 - 新疾病出现, 人们消失, 然后你们出现了
- And you think we did it!
- Oh, come on, we haven't done a thing!
- 那你就觉得是我们干的？  - 哦, 得了, 我们什么也没干！
Perhaps maybe, I don't know who you are,
what you are, or where you came from,
也许吧, 我也不知道你们是谁, 是干什么的, 从哪里来
but you can get off the moon now!
但你们现在就可以离开月球了！
- Well, that suits me fine, the sooner the better!
- No, Ben, we can't go yet.
- 好啊, 正想走呢, 越早越好！  - 不, Ben, 我们还不能走
- Why not? They don't want us here.
- Because there is something evil here. We must stay.
- 为什么不？他们不想让我们在这里 - 因为这里有邪恶的东西, 我们必须留下来
- Evil? Don't be daft!
- Evil is what I meant.
- 邪恶？ 别犯傻了！   - 邪恶．我说的就是这个
There are some corners of the universe
which have bred the most terrible things.
宇宙中有些角落会孕育出最可怕的东西
Things which act against everything
that we believe in. They must be fought.
这些东西会跟我们所信仰的一切作对．我们必须跟他们斗争
This disease, for instance. It isn't really
a disease at all, but I can help you with it.
举例来说, 这个疾病, 其实并不是一种病．但我可以帮助你们
You'll see. I'll find the cause for you.
你会看到, 我会帮你们找到原因
- Will you, indeed?
- Yes, certainly. I just need to examine a few things. That's all.
- 会吗, 真的？ - 当然．我需要先检验几样东西, 仅此而已
- It should be simple.
- Well, I'm not sure.
- 那很简单  - 嗯, 我不太确定
I'll give you just one Earth-day cycle to find the cause.
我给你一个地球日的时间来寻找原因
- Earth what?
- 24 hours.
- 地球什么？  - ２４小时
- But that's no time at all.
- It's all you're going to get.
- 但这时间也太短了吧  - 你们只有这些时间
Then you get off the moon, with this bloke here.
然后你们就离开月球, 带着这个家伙
- You can't move him! He's very ill.
- We accept.
- 你不能乱动他, 他病得很厉害  - 我们接受
Now tell me, you have pathological equipment here, yes?
现在说说, 你们这里有病理分析设备吧？
Yes. Evans was working on an extensive research project.
It's all in here.
有．Evans 之前在做一个扩展研究项目．东西都在这里
It's quite a small unit. We're not equipped
to deal with a full-scale epidemic.
是一套小型设备, 我们并没有针对大规模传染病的配置
- Do you think you can manage?
- Yes. I think I can.
- 你觉得你能搞定吗？ - 是的，我觉得我能
Right. I'll leave you to it. Don't forget - 24 hours.
好, 我就不打扰你了．不要忘了 - ２４小时
- What are you going to do, Doctor?
- We'll start with this one.
- 你打算怎么做, 博士？ - 我们从这个开始
- Are you really a medical doctor?
- Yes, I think I was once
- 你真是一个医学博士吗？  - 是的, 我想我曾经做过
Polly, I think I took a degree once, in Glasgow.
Polly, 我记得我拿到了学位, 在格拉斯哥
1888, I think. Lister. Hold that for me, will you?
1888年, 没记错的话. 李斯特．帮我端着这个, 行吗
（约瑟夫-李斯特 英国外科医生, 外科手术消毒技术的发明者和推广者）
- Oh!
- All right. He's quite unconscious.
- 噢！  - 没事, 他完全没意识了
- What can we do to help?
- I shall need to examine everything.
- 我们能帮什么忙吗？ - 我需要检查所有东西
Clothes, boots, food, towels, soap - everything.
衣服、鞋子、食物、毛巾、肥皂, 所有东西
Will you get them for me, please?
你能给我拿来吗？
- Have you any idea what it might be?
- No. Not an idea.
- 你有头绪吗, 可能是什么？  - 没有, 完全没头绪
But we'll find it out.
但我们会找出来的
I don't understand it. I'm sure
there's a lack of co-ordination somewhere.
我搞不懂了, 我肯定这里这里某个地方不太协调fixme
- Yes, but where?
- On the indicators. Look!
- 是, 但是哪儿呢？  - 在指示器上, 看！
- It should be steady as a rock.
- The fault must be in the Gravitron.
- 应该非常平稳了  - 故障肯定在在引力创里面
- Nils, here.
- Yes.
- Nils, 过来  - 好
We're going to run a test. Move the probe. /21.5
我们来做个测试。移动探针
We'll see if the indicators
move the right distance on the map.
我们看看指示器在地图上移动的距离是否正确
- Keep an eye on the probe itself, will you?
- OK.
- 留意着点探针, 行吗？  - 行
- All yours.
- Right.
Deflect probe five degrees... now.
将探针偏转５度...启动！
Way off. Five degrees should put them
over Iceland. Move the probe back again.
错得厉害．５度应该到冰岛上面了．把探针再移动回来
The probe seemed to deflects all right.
探针偏转没问题
The fault must be here. This could be a major disaster
if we can't stabilise the Earth's field.
问题肯定在这个地方．如果我们不能稳定住地球域(?),将会是灾难
If we lose that hurricane,
all hell will break loose on Earth.
如果我们没跟住飓风, 所有地狱噩梦都会被放出来
- I have a wife and family.
- You're not the only one.
- 我还有老婆和家庭  - 又不止你有
Roget, check the potentiometers.
Roget, 检查一下电压计
Nils, check the gravitation units.
Nils, 检查引力读数
Shake it up. We haven't got much time.
快点动起来, 我们没有太多时间
- The field is stabilising at 48, Mr Hobson.
- Prepare to move probe.
- 此领域稳定在 48 , Hobson先生  - 准备移动探针
Check co-ordinates.
检查坐标
We've got to hold that hurricane in the Pacific.
我们得把那个飓风控制在太平洋
Stand by... Now!
预备...开始！
20-degree tilt complete.
20度倾斜完成
The field's not correcting.
fixme
- We'll have to increase the reactor power.
- You can't do that. The torus will burn out.
- 我们只能加大反应器功率了  - 不能这么干, 托环会烧坏的
It's all we can do.
我们只能这么干
International Space Control.
Earth calling Moon Weather Control. Stand by. Stand by the controller.
国际空间控制中心．地球站呼叫天气控制中心月球站．请待命FIXME
This is Moonbase. Come in, please.
这里是月球基地, 请回话
- We wish to speak to Mr Hobson.
- Hobson speaking.
- 我们期望同 Hobson 先生对话  - 我正是 Hobson
- Stand by for the Controller.
- Right. He's actually going to speak to us this time!
- 准备与控制员对话  - 好，这次他真要跟我们说话了！
Controller Rinberg speaking.
我是控制员Rinberg
- Is that you, Hobson?
- Yes, Rinberg.
- 是你吗, Hobson？  - 是的, Rinberg
The directional fields are showing a progressive error.
fixme =
There are widespread pressure fluctuations
in Atlantic Zone 6.
在大西洋６区上有大面积的压力变动
You must get the Gravitron back into balance.
你们必须让引力创回归平衡
We're trying to compensate by realigning the probe.
我们正在重新调节探针, 尽力补救
We have an error in the servos.
但我们的伺服器有错误
Well, there's no sign of any improvement here.
但是，这里没有改善的迹象
We've just had a report from Miami, Florida.
我们刚受到了佛罗里达迈阿密的报告
30 minutes ago, they were enjoying
clear skies and a heatwave.
30分钟以前, 他们还在享受蓝天和热风
Now Hurricane Lucy is right overhead.
但现在飓风 Lucy 已经到了他们头上
- The only thing we can do is shut it down.
- Switch the Gravitron off?
- 我们唯一能做的就是关掉它  - 关闭引力创?
Yes. It's the only chance.
是的，这是唯一的机会
We can't do that, man. The collapse of the gravity would devastate
half the globe.
我们不能那么干，伙计。引力陡降会让半个地球都遭殃的
- There'd be storms, hurricanes...
- I overheard your conversation.
- 将会有暴雨、飓风 ...  - 我听到了你们的对话
It's quite out of the question.
这是绝不可能的
You're not to shut down the Gravitron
under any circumstances. That's an order.
你们在任何情况下都不能关闭引力创．这是项命令
I...I think perhaps you don't appreciate
how serious the situation already is.
我...我想或许你们不了解情况已经是多么严重
I bet he gets a knighthood
我打赌他有骑士情结
We spent years in the general assembly negotiating
methods of agreement between farmers and landowners.
我们花了多年时间与农民和地主磋商协议的方式
Now the weather's out of control,
they're after our blood.
现在天气失控了, 他们会要我们的命的
I must say, I can't blame them.
You've got to get that thing under control - quickly.
我得说, 我不怪他们．你们得把那个东西回归可控状态 - 要快
Now please get on with it.
现在请去干吧
Earth Control over and out.
地球控制中心结束退出
Now you're all in the picture. Well, we've got trouble.
Bad trouble. We haven't got much time.
现在, 整体情况大家都知道了．我们有了麻烦, 大麻烦．我们没有太多时间
We're going to run through every circuit,
every field pattern, every nut and bolt
我要去检查每个线路, 每个域模式, 每个螺母和螺栓
until Charlie boy's running sweet and smooth.
A full class A test, in fact.
直到那玩意儿重新欢快平顺地跑起来．事实上, 要做一次完整的A级测试
You all know what to do. Let's get on with it.
We'll start on the main tape programme.
你们都知道要做什么了．我们开始干吧．我们从主磁带程序开始
It's running now.
开始运行了
Give me the analogue value on module six, will you?
给我模块６的模拟数值, 好吗
They look all right.
它们看起来没问题
A at ten millivolts.
A实例是 10M 伏特
B at 15 millivolts.
B实例是 15M 伏特
- C at 26. That fits, doesn't it?
- Yes, they're at normal levels.
- C 是 26．这没问题, 是吧?  - 是的, 他们都在正常水平
Finish checking here, will you?
The answer may be in the control panel.
你完成这里的检查, 行吗？答案也许在控制面板上
I'll sing out the binary conversion values.
You check them on readout.
我来唱读二元转换读书, 你负责核对
Channel one.
第一通道
- Eight...   - Right.
- 八...  - 对
- One.    - Mm.
- 一      - 嗯
- Three. Four.   - Yeah.
- 三．四     - 对
- Six. Eight. Twelve.  - Yeah.
- 六．八．十二     - 对
All spot-on.
都没问题
Qu'est-ce que vous fabriquez ici? Vous croyez
que nous sommes en train de nous amuser?
(法语)
- Come on. Get out of the way!
- Enchant, monsieur
- 嘿, 别在这里碍事  - ... (法语)
Now, where were we?
现在, 我们到哪儿了
Ah, yes, the fluid servo primers.
I reckon this is probably where the fault is.
啊, 是了, 流体伺服器油泵．我觉得这可能是问题所在了
- Do you want them all?
- The main tank will do.
- 所有你都要吗？  - 主箱的就行了
- Header one. 45 pounds.
- Yes.
- 一号枪, 45磅  - 好
- Header two. 47.
- Yes.
- 二号枪, 47磅  - 好
- Three. 42.
- Yes.
- 三号枪, 42  - 好
Sine values equivalent.
They all fit. Nothing there.
都没问题, 没啥了
It must be the potentiometer net, then.
那就肯定是电位计了
It'll take us some time to do that.
We'll need the digital voltmeter.
这要费点时间, 我们需要数字电压表
What the blazes are you doing?
你到底在搞什么鬼啊
- I'm collecting specimens.
- Specimens?
- 我在采集样本  - 样本？
Oh, yes... Well, get on with it.
哦, 是了...好了, 干吧
We're nearly out of this interferon stuff.
这些干扰素快用完了
- You'd better ask Mr Hobson where the rest is.
- Right.
- 你最好去问问 Hobson 先生剩余的在那里  - 好
It's all right, Jamie. It's all right.
You're going to get better but you must lie still.
没事的, Jamie, 没事．你会好起来的, 但你必须要躺好
What is this place? Is it the home of the piper?
这是什么地方？这是风笛手的家吗？
No, we're on the moon. You know, the moon up in the sky.
不, 我们在月球上．你知道吗, 天上的月亮
No, I can't be alive.
不, 我不可能还活着
I've just seen the piper.
我刚才看见了风笛手
The piper! I knew!
风笛手！我就知道！
Polly! What's happened?
Polly! 发生了什么事？
Polly.
Are you all right?
你没事吧？
Anything out on the probe servers?
外面探针服务器有问题吗？
There's a slight discrepancy... in normal limits.
- What about the overall feedback valve? We haven't checked it.
- That's an idea.
- 总反馈阀怎么样？我们还没检查过它
- 是个主意
You know I don't think it's likely to be a mechanical fault.
知道吗，我觉得这不太可能是机械故障
- Mr. Hobson, an air pressure drop again.
- Same as before? /20.3
- Hobson 先生，又一次出现气压了。 - 跟以前一样吗
Yes. Just the same. Lasts about five seconds.
是的, 一样，持续了大约5秒钟
Something's odd. It's not the pumps. I'm sure of that./26.4
这很奇怪，不是泵的问题。我肯定。
Has anyone asked permission to leave the base?
有人请求离开基地吗？
No. As far as I know, the compression chamber's empty.
不。就我所知，压缩舱是空的
If I find anybody's been fooling about in there
without my permission, I'll tear the hides off them!
如果我发现谁没有得到允许就在那里面瞎搞，我要把他们的皮都撕掉!
- The pressure's up again now, sir.
- Thank heaven.
- 压力又回升了，头儿  - 感谢上天
- I'll check over the control loop monitor.
- You're wasting your time.
- 我会检查控制回路监视器  - 你是在浪费时间
Nothing's a waste of time till we trace this fault!
只要能找到问题没什么是浪费时间
You saw what's happening on Earth.
We can't afford to miss anything. Get on with it!
你都看见地球上发生了什么。遗漏了什么地方我们承担不起。赶紧吧
I've found something.
It's one of the probe control antennae.
我发现点问题，是其中一个探针控制天线
- What's wrong with it?
- Two pieces are missing. It's not co-ordinating.
- 它怎么了  - 有
- Missing?
- Meteorites?
Could be. There could be a simpler explanation.
When did these people arrive here?
The end of period 11 in this present lunar day.
- When did the Gravitron start playing up?
- The beginning of period 12.
- When was the last time anyone was outside?
- During period 13.
- Two men realigned a solar mirror.
- That's it!
- I'm not with you.
- It's simple.
Strangers arrive period 11.
- The Gravitron fails period 12.
- I understand, but...
It's time we put that Doctor and his friend
in cold storage.
Just a second. Get two men outside
to look at the antennae, will you?
Joe, tell Jules and Franz
I want them here pretty sharpish.
- What is it?
- Another patient's gone, sir.
What?! Come on!
Nothing. Absolutely nothing.
没有，什么都没有
- Isn't there any clue at all?
- No. It's a complete blank.
- 一点线索也没有吗？  - 没有, 完全的空白
All the tests are negative. As far as I can see,
this whole ridiculous place is sterile.
所有测试结果都是阴性的．就我所看到的来说, 这整个破地方都是无菌的
- We'll have to tell Mr Hobson, I suppose.
- 我们不得不跟 Hobson 先生说了, 我想
I don't like it very much. I simply don't understand it.
我不喜欢这个结果。我就是想不明白
Doctor, it couldn't possibly have
anything to do with Lister, could it?
博士, 这会不会跟李斯特有关, 可能吗？
- Lister?
- Well, I mean, you did say...
- 李斯特  - 这样, 我是说, 你不是说
that you took your degree in Glasgow in 1888.
你1888年在格拉斯哥拿到了学位
That's an awfully long time from now, 2070, whatever it is.
那可是一段好长的时间了, 现在是2070年了
Polly, are you suggesting that
I'm not confident to carry out these tests?
Polly, 你是不是想说我并没有能力进行这些检测？
No, No, I'm just wondering if there was anything
that Joseph Lister didn't know in 1888
不, 不, 我只是在想会不会有些什么东西是约瑟夫-李斯特在1888年不知道的
- that might help you now.
- Ssh! Somebody's coming!
- 说不定可以帮上你  - 嘘, 有人来了！
It's Mr Hobson. Out for blood - ours. Look busy! Quick!
是 Hobson 先生． 去拿血样 - 我们的．装作忙碌, 快！
That's the third person to disappear in the past few hours.
这是在过去几个小时内消失的第三个人了
- It's completely illogical.
- Do you mind?
- 这完全没逻辑  - 可以吗？
Would you mind standing away from the door
and allowing it to close? The slides. The dust!
你别站在门边可以吗, 让门可以关上？检测片. 灰尘！
It must be you people.
We've got some straight talking to do, you and I.
肯定是你的人．我们得好好谈一谈了, 你跟我
- Polly. Another boot.
- Do you hear me?
- Polly, 再来一下  - 你听到我的话了吗？
- This is extraordinary. Look here.
- Excuse me, please.
- 这真是不寻常啊, 看这里  - 借过一下, 请
Excuse me. We ARE trying to help you.
对不起, 我们正在试图帮你忙呢
- Help? Is that what you call it? You can all get off the moon now.
- No, wait a minute. You said...
- 帮忙？你管这个叫帮忙？你们现在就可以离开月球了 - 不, 等一下, 你说过...
- I don't care what I said!  - Ah!
- 我不管我说过什么！  - 哈！
- Have you found something?
- I think perhaps I have.
- 你发现什么了吗？  - 我想也许我发现了
Yes, I may be onto something, but I must have some room.
是的, 我可能找到点头绪, 但我必须得有空间
How can I work under these conditions? Now, please,
come along. Outside. I'm trying to work in here!
在这种条件下我怎么工作？ 现在, 请过来, 外面去．我在这里尽力工作呢
- Ben, see that they stay outside.
- Did you mean that?
- Ben, 确保他们待在外面  - 你真的吗？
- What?
- You've found something?
- 什么？  - 你发现了点什么？
Oh, Polly, I only wish I had.
哦, Polly, 我也期望我是
Keep them happy with coffee while I think of something.
用咖啡让他们乐呵乐呵, 我再想想怎么弄
All right.
好吧
Here, Doctor.
过来, 博士
- Completed your examination?
- Yes.
- 完成检验了吗？  - 是的
- Have you poked into everything?
- Yes, clothes, boots, food.
- 翻出什么了吗？  - 翻了衣服＼鞋子＼食物
- And you've found...
- Absolutely nothing.
- 你发现．．．  - 什么也没有
Just as I thought, so what I told you still stands.
跟我想的一样, 所以我跟你说的还是成立
Ah, coffee. Splendid.
啊, 咖啡, 太好了
Thank you, Polly. I think we could all do with a cup!
谢谢你, Polly．我觉得我们都需要一杯
See how Jules and Franz are getting on.
看看 Jules 和 Franz 进展如何
Right.
好的
- Coffee? Sugar?
- Hello, Doctor. Thank you.
- 要咖啡不？ 糖？  - 你好, 博士．谢谢你
- It's very hot. Doctor, what about you?
- Thank you, Polly.
- 这很热. 博士, 你要吗？ - 谢谢你, Polly
Doctor, as I was saying, you've had your chance.
You come up with absolutely nothing.
博士, 如我之前说过的, 给过你们机会了．但你什么也没有发现
Don't touch him!
别碰他！
Let me look.
我看看
Charlie and you, Ben, give us a hand
to get him into the medical unit.
Charlie 和你 Ben, 搭一下手, 把他弄到医务室去
Try not to touch his skin.
尽量不要碰到他的皮肤
Don't drink that! It's the sugar!
不要喝那个！是糖！
Don't you see? That's why the disease doesn't affect everyone.
你明白了吗？那就是为什么这个病没有感染每一个人
It's the sugar. Not everyone takes it.
是糖有问题, 不是每个人都加糖
Don't touch it.
别碰它TS
- What are you doing?
- Just be patient.
- 你在干什么  - 耐心点
Just as I thought.
正如我所料想的
A large neurotropic virus.
一种大型的神经病毒
- Like the space plague?
- No.
- 就像太空瘟疫? - 不
（注: 太空瘟疫是科幻小说 Highways in Hiding 所描绘的一种疾病,
初始表象是手指脚趾硬化, 然后扩散到四肢以及全身. 此小说的简略版名称即为"太空瘟疫")
It's a large infective agent that only attacks the nerves.
这是一种大型感染剂, 只攻击神经系统
That's why these patients got these lines
appear on faces and hands.
这就是为什么那些病人脸上手上会出现那些条纹
It follows the course of the nerves under the skin.
它沿着皮下的神经脉络走动
That's _ it well. But how did it get in here?
但它怎么进入这个地方的？
It is the Cybermen. I believe they have
deliberately infected the base.
是赛博人．我相信是他们故意感染了这个基地
My men have searched every square of the base.
我的人搜索了这个基地的每一寸地方FIXMTS/
There's no space to hide a cat, let alone a Cyberman.
这个地方连只猫都没地方躲, 更别说赛博人了FIXTS/
Anyhow, how did they get in?
不管怎么说, 他们怎么进来的
- One moment.
- What is it?
- 等一下  - 什么
- You say you searched all the base?
- Yes. What of it?
- 你说你们把整个基地搜遍了？ - 是啊, 怎么？
- No chance of anyone hiding anywhere?
- None whatever.
- 任何人没有机会躲在什么地方？  - 没有任何机会
Did your men search in here? Did they?
你的人搜过这里吗？搜过没？
- There was'nt people in here, so...
- Did they search in here?
- 之前这里没有人, 所以... - 他们搜过这里没有？
- No.
- There's nowhere in here they could hide.
- 没有  - 这里没有可以躲藏的地方
Oh, no! Back!
噢, 不！后退！
Back.
后退